Hello tiktakers how are you today
we have grabbed the globe to
decide on our next travel destination and
you know what we have gone all
out and we are going to see one of the
seven wonders of the modern world are you
coming we are talking about Machu Picchu have you
ever seen photographs of them we have
been amazed this is an
ancient Inca city listed as a
World Heritage Site by UNESCO it is
located in the Andes mountain range
in Peru its name
means something like old mountain and
nothing could be further from the truth because it is
located about
2453 m above sea level and was
built in the mid-15th century it is
believed that Pachacutec lived there the ninth
ruler of the
Inca state in addition to its extremely high
historical value this town is considered
a masterpiece of architecture and
engineering it was rediscovered in 1911 by
the American explorer Hiran
Bingham and since then
its possible origin has not stopped being studied through
the almost 200 constructions that
we find there among them the temple to the sun
the only  circular building of the
city that is built on a
huge natural rock is incredible the
things they did in the past without
machines to
help them in the city there is also a
kind of medieval tower temples in
honor of inti the sun or the Condor a
royal palace the temple of the three
windows and many more things tic tackers they
even have a sacred stone
that for many is the most important thing
in the place Machu Picchu is surrounded by
mystery and enigmas of course the whole
area has a great spirituality
some say that if you touch that
sacred stone that has carved the shapes of
the surrounding mountains and you concentrate
you can perfectly feel its
energy I don't know if you believe in these things
tic tackers but without a doubt the place
deserves to be given the benefit of the doubt
for the Incas these stones carved in
harmony with nature were
sacred points what they called
hakas now we know that in Machu Picchu
different neighborhoods were mixed the
upper part was urban and the lower agricultural
there were hierarchies that were
evident in their constructions all
surrounded by the purest and most
spectacular nature if one day  If you decide to
visit it you have to be careful with
altitude sickness which can be dangerous for those of us who are not
used to it.
Also, prepare for the
welcome you will receive from the llamas
that roam freely throughout the area. We
also know this from the large
number of people who come to the
place every day. In addition, the area is
betting on sustainable and
environmentally friendly tourism and we are
delighted with this dec tiktakers such a
wonder deserves to be taken care of. We
look forward to taking that
plane before saying goodbye as we know
that you are True Lovers of
terror we leave you with a video where we
explain some of the worst
human sacrifices that the Inca society
practiced in
ancient times. The Inca civilization is one
of the most famous and fascinating of
antiquity, in addition to its constructions, it is
known for carrying out
human sacrifices. One of the most
shocking was the capacocha where
minors were sacrificed. There are dozens
of mummies as proof of these
practices. The capacocha translates as
royal obligation one of the most
important rituals of the Inc calendar in which
boys and girls were sacrificed
which were selected depending on
their health physical appearance and
family were held in parties to
the gods for the coronation or death
of the Inca governor and also to
propitiate good harvests or ward off
disasters such as plagues droughts famines
or volcanic eruptions. For the
imperial capacocha of each of the
Inca territories,
several boys and girls between 6 and 10
years old were sent to Cuzco who were handsome without any
disease stain or scar and from good
families especially children of Caciques
for them they were the purest beings their
families gave their child to the state
as a tribute most of them
considered this act a great honor in
the case of girls an exception could be made
with their age reaching
16 years as long as they had not
yet had
[Music]
relations approximately one year before
the sacrifice they proceeded to choose the
boy or girl they walked long distances
in the direction of Cuzco there the Inca
predicted the ceremonies of the election of the
child who would be sacrificed the minors
traveled escorted by a group of does
and companions towards the city  They were
dressed in the finest clothes and
treated with privileges. The rites could
last for several weeks, during which
ritual dances were performed, offerings
of gold and silver objects,
seashells, and
animal sacrifices were made. The selected boys
traveled directly to Cuzco, the
Inca capital. The girls went first to the clasi or
house of the chosen women to
meet the muna, a group of
matriarchs similar to nuns. These
women were in charge of educating the
girls in the arts of weaving, sewing,
and the preparation of chicha, a
spiritual drink. Not all who reached
the mam cuna were destined to die as
sacrifices. Some of them
stayed in the llasi and were consecrated as
priestesses to help raise other
girls. Another group traveled to Cuzco to
enter the service of the emperor. The
third group of girls were those who would
die in the capacocha ritual.
[Music]
During these ceremonies, the children were
sanctified as children of the Sun and
received gifts appropriate to their new
status, such as high-quality cumbi fabrics.
These fabrics were a symbol of
belonging in kaik  Even chiefs and
caciques were prohibited from using it, then
the Inca and the priests presided over the
symbolic marriage ceremony of
girls and boys, the daughter of the chief of a
village married the son of the chief of
another, establishing genealogical ties.
When the ceremonies were over, the
children, the priests and their entourage of
companions began the journey
back to their communities. Upon returning, they did not
follow the royal road or
Linca road as they had done when they left, but rather they
had to follow a straight path. It
did not matter how difficult or
dangerous it was, it was a long journey through
valleys, rivers and mountains that could last for
months. Upon arriving at their towns, they were
received with great celebrations by the
locals and after these celebrations they
went in procession to the place
of
sacrifice. The offering ceremony
had different characteristics in each
place. In most cases, the
children were drugged with an
alcoholic drink made from corn called chicha and
coca leaves. Some sources assure that the
children ingested these natural drugs
for days before the ceremony
so that they would die happy, for the
gods they felt nothing.  They were
drugged their unconscious bodies were deposited
in the place of the
ceremony exposed to temperatures of
20 gr and died of hypothermia in other
cases they accelerated their death causing it in a
more violent way with a strong
blow to the head to others with
puncture wounds in their thorax and strangulations were also
practiced
human sacrifices were considered a means to
establish a direct connection with the
gods through these rituals the
Incas sought to obtain divine favor and
ensure the protection and prosperity of
their empire it was believed that the
sacrificed victims acted as
intermediaries carrying the requests and
needs of the people before the
divinities on the other hand these rituals
served to reaffirm the hierarchy and the
power of the ruler who was
considered a representative of the
gods on earth participation in
these events strengthened the identity and
union of the community by bringing its
members together around a common and
sacred cause so far
several discoveries related to
the capacocha have been found the most famous bodies found
are the Queen of the Hill the child
of the Hill the lead the mummy  Juanita and
the children of Yuyay
Yako The Queen of the Hill also known
as the mummy of Cerro Chuska is a mummy
found in the province of Salta
Argentina in Cerro Chuska it is estimated that she
was between 8 and 9 years old and that she was
sacrificed between 1400 and 1532 in a
capacocha ceremony
her tomb was found between 1920 and
1922 by a vaqueano and a miner who
violated her tomb with dynamite they
extracted the mummified body of the
girl along with textiles and objects of
great value they lowered the mummy to
Tolombón and the inhabitants named her
The Queen of the Hill while she
was there they put candles
around her and gave her offerings Shortly
after a merchant and
collector named Pedro Mendoza appeared he
bought it and moved it to Cafayate to
add this piece to his great collection he
exhibited it in one of his large homes
charging admission to see it some time
later Mendoza sold the mummy to another
collector Perfecto Bustamante who
also put the mummy on display in
his business premises after  it was sold to
absor pedersen in exchange for a
gas installation pedersen was an
engineer and amateur archaeologist he
placed the mummy in the basement of his
house with other archaeological objects
where it remained without any care
for 50 years years and later it would pass
through different hands
[Music]
but both the body of the girl and the
objects of great value with which she was
buried suffered the consequences
of the illegal trafficking of cultural goods
and little by little it was stripped of the
elements that accompanied it after
eight decades wandering through different
private collections basements and closets
the mummy and the few objects that were
recovered have been exhibited since 2006 in
the Museum of High Mountain Archaeology
although it is in great
deterioration with the studies carried out on
the mummy it was determined that the cause of
death was a puncture wound in the
right AX emitter that entered through its
back this is reinforced by the
expression of pain that the
mummy presents its hair was combed
with fine braids it was striking
that it did not have any shoes but there is a
possibility that it lost them in
the  times that it was changing owners
the same thing happened with the
statuettes and objects of gold and silver that are
said to have accompanied the
mummy the locals came to mention
quantities of 4 to 5 kilos of gold and as
many of silver but probably in
the years of the discovery
someone would have kept them the
deterioration suffered It is evident in the
comparison with photographs that were
obtained previously the mummy
completely lost almost all of its
hair and a large part of the skin of the
skull it is also not known with certainty
how many pieces of stone were lost
another known case of Inca sacrifice is
the child of Cerro el plomo it was the first
discovery of an
excellently preserved body at high
altitude enclosing the lead it was found by
three men who began an excursion
in search of some treasure first
they found the child He had his arms
wrapped around his legs and his
head rested on his right shoulder and arm
before he died he covered his
legs with his short tunic trying to
protect himself from the intense cold his eyes
were closed and it seemed that he was sleeping
peacefully the hikers spent
the night on the mountain and the
next day they chose to descend alone  with
the objects without the body they left
buried and hidden in a cave
after they tried to get
rewards for their discovery finally they
received a payment of 45,000 pesetas to
integrate it into the collection of the
Natural History Museum of
Chile thanks to the characteristics of the climate the
body had been preserved in optimal
conditions giving the impression of
being in front of a
sleeping individual and that could wake up at
any moment when the
discovery was made this was a frozen corpse and
its conservation was due only to its
permanence for several centuries in an
environment whose temperature was below 0
gr the mummification process began with
the transfer of the body to other
climatic conditions where the
discoverers kept it
for five weeks and later in
Santiago de Chile but in no way was it
an artificially prepared mummy
like for example the
Egyptians but the product of a
natural process was dressed for the ceremony
with a dark wool shirt a blanket
that covered his back and on his feet he
wore leather moccasins his
face painted red with ochre stripes and his
hair was combed with more than 200
braids on his right forearm he had a
bracelet  wide silver and on his
head he wore a black wool headdress
crowned with feathers was placed in
a chamber excavated in the place
called burial and later
covered with Lajas nearby was
buried a female statuette of
silver and other symbolic ornaments
[Music]
after the Incas
finished the ceremony they resumed the
journey back and the child was left
alone despite the fact that the little one was
drowsy with the drugs that had been
given to him the height of the mountain was so
extreme that he curled up in fetal mode
to protect himself from the cold his body
temperature was dropping until
hypothermia caused his death it was
proven that in the last moments of
life he vomited and defecated on himself
[Music]
the child of Cerro el plomo
is in the National Museum of
Natural History of Chile until the
1980s it was exposed to the public
however due to the deterioration that it began to
experience it was transferred to the
anthropology area of the museum to guarantee
its optimal preservation currently in the
Museum a replica of the body is shown
while the original only has
access to
researchers regarding the mummy
Juanita was discovered in
1995 on an expedition to the Ampato volcano
two men saw a lump
inside the crater and upon approaching
they discovered that it was the body
of a very well preserved girl
around it had several offerings such as
gold statuettes and several plants
after conducting the studies they
confirmed that Juanita died at 13 or
14 years old she was a healthy girl without any
illness she was found holding her
umbilical cord which had probably been
kept specifically for her
sacrifice indicating that she had been
selected to be sacrificed
before her birth she had a
5 cm fissure in her skull and
internal bleeding which was what triggered her
death it is said that she had probably been
given a large blow to the head
while she was kneeling Juanita was
found frozen and therefore her
remains and clothing were
naturally preserved like that of Cerro el Pólvora
her skin organs tissues blood hair
stomach contents and clothing
were very well preserved offering
scientists details of the
Inca culture Juanita's body is
in the Sandinos Sanctuary Museum in
Peru as for  to other of the most
important discoveries in
1999 near the summit of the Yuya
Yaco volcano three child mummies were found
the boy Ella and the girl of the
Lightning known as the mummies of Yuya
Yaco were also in very good condition
due to the freezing temperatures in
which they were preserved and today are
exhibited in the Museum of Archaeology of
High Mountain of Salta although it was already known
that alcohol and coca were
decisive in the human sacrifices
of the Incas the remains found in the
hair allowed to deduce new
details about how these
rituals were prepared so a year before dying the
diet of the maiden the eldest of
the children changed drastically
apparently at that time she would have been
chosen for the sacrifice and since
then they offered her more
animal protein which not everyone could have
access to the coca leaves that are used
as raw material for cocaine
produce among others a calming effect
when chewed mixed with ash the
Incas believed that the states of
intoxication allowed access to the world of
the Spirits this and alcohol were
substances that caused  a change of
state with considered sacred in addition
these drugs also contributed to
children being more docile to
the
[Music]
rituals the first body located was
the boy of approximately 7 years of
age was sitting on a
gray tunic with his face directed towards the Sun He
had short hair an ornament of
white feathers wrapped around his
head and an ornament on the chest the
second discovery a few meters from the child
was the maiden a young woman of 15 years old
wore a headdress of feathers on her head
in her face still preserved remains of
red pigments and in her mouth remains of
Coca leaf her hair was combed
with small braids the third discovery
corresponded to a small girl of 6
years of age who was sitting with her
legs bent and her head
held high looking towards the southwest at
some point the discharge of lightning
penetrated more than 1 meter into the ground and
struck her damaging part of her body and her
clothes for this reason she is known as the Girl
of the Lightning her hair is combed with two
small braids that come out of her forehead
and wore as an ornament a metal plate
her eyes were closed  and the
half-open mouth revealing the
teeth the remains found of
all these children allowed us to
learn today part of the history of the
Incas and how they carried out these
human sacrifices criticism from
some sectors of these studies
focuses on respect for
cultural tradition as well as who owns the
archaeological remains these groups maintain that
the removal of the children's bodies
configures a
desecration you What do you think
should they leave these mummies buried
respecting the sacred actions of
ancestors or do you agree with their
use for research purposes and
exhibition in museums we
read you Do not forget to subscribe and give a
Like if you liked it And you can also
follow us on our social networks
Facebook Twitter and Instagram until the
next video
[Music]